Couch Family Papers, 1713-1858 Ms 5 Ms 5
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Couch Family Papers, 1713-1858
Ms 5
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.5 Linear feet
This collection contains personal and financial papers from the Couch family of Fairfield, CT in the 18th and 19th centuries.
(1 box, 275 items, 2 oversize items)
Couch family
Couch, Simon, 1729-1809
Couch, Simon, b. 1788
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
This Couch family settled in Fairfield in the middle of the 17th century. As the collection indicates, these were people of property. Many of the items belonged to Simon Couch (1729-1809) who settled in Green's Farms and was a farmer, merchant, town official and tax collector. His daughter Abigail married William Sherwood. More genealogical information can be found in the following:
The History of Fairfield by Elizabeth Hubbell Schenck, New York, 1889. History and Genealogy of the Families of Old Fairfield, Vol. I, Part I by Donald Lines Jacobus, Fairfield, CT, 1930.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of one box containing bills, correspondence, deeds, financial records and legal papers, real estate papers, wills, Yale school papers and ledgers. Of particular note is Folder K with indenture servant and slave papers. There are two oversize items: Simon Couch, Jr.'s Practical Survey Work Book and a genealogy of the Couch family.
The deeds, misc. ledgers and writs are listed by date. All other categories are alphabetized.
Related Archival Materials note
The papers in this collection interrelate with the Sherwood Papers, MS 7.
Sherwood, Abigail Couch, 1782-1858; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Greens Farms (Conn.); Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Receipts (financial records)
- Bills and Bills Receipted, 1786-1832; Folder A; 15.0 items
  - Daniel Andrews
  - Joseph B. Couch
  - Sam. B. Sherwood
  - Simon Couch, 3.0 items
  - William Couch, 8.0 items
  - Unidentified
- Business Correspondence, 1805-1819; Folder B; 23.0 items
  - From Wm. Couch to Simon Sherwood, 1805-1819; 3.0 items
  - From Wm. Couch to Wm. Sherwood, 1805-1812; 20.0 items
- Business Correspondence, Folder C; 15.0 items
  - From Wm. Couch to William Sherwood, 1813-1821
- Personal Correspondence, 1803-1818; Folder D; 10.0 items
  - Abigail Couch to Simon Couch, 1804
  - Hiram Couch to Wm. Sherwood, 1817
  - Simon Couch to Simon Couch, Jr., 1803-1805; 3.0 items
  - Wm. Couch to Abigail Couch, 1818
  - Wm. Couch to Simon Couch, 1804-1805; 3.0 items
  - Wm. Couch to William Sherwood, 1804
- Deeds, 1713-1799; Folder E; 22.0 items
  - From Joseph Wakeman to Simon Couch, 1738
  - From Martha Goreham to Mary Couch, 1779
  - From Josiah Couch to Mary Couch, 1781
  - From Hezekiah and Sarah Banks to Simon Couch, 1783
  - From Simon Couch Jr. to Simon Couch, 1789
  - From Dennie Chapman to Simon Couch, 1789
  - From William Heron, et al. to Simon Couch, 1791
  - From Simon Couch, Jr. to Simon Couch, 1792
  - From Thomas Nash to Simon Couch, 1794
  - From Daniel Chapman to Simon Couch, 1795
  - From Lovel Chapman to Simon Couch, 1795
  - From Gershom Bulkley to Simon Couch, 1795
  - From James Chapman, Jr. to Simon Couch, 1796
  - From John Green to Abigail Couch, 1713
  - From David and Mary Couch to Joseph Couch, 1797
  - From Joseph Couch to David and Mary Couch, 1797
  - From Burr Jennings to Simon Couch, 1797
  - From Thomas and Abigail Davis to Simon Couch, 1798
  - From David Hubill to Simon Couch, 1799
  - From Lovell Chapman to Simon Couch, 1799
  - From Jeremiah Osborn to Simon Couch, 1799
  - From Stephen and Stephen Godfrey, Jr. to Simon Couch, 1799
- Deeds, 1801-1822; Folder F; 27.0 items
  - From Jere Davis to Simon Couch, 1801
  - From Burr Jennings to Simon Couch, 1801
  - From Ebenezer Coley to Joseph Couch, 1802
  - From Joseph Taylor to Joseph Couch, 1805
  - From Moses Taylor to Joseph Couch, 1805
  - From Simon Couch to Simon Couch, Jr., 1805
  - From Simon Couch to Wm. Sherwood, 1806
  - From Simon Couch to Abigail Sherwood, 1808
  - From Wm. and Simon Couch to Abigail Sherwood, 1808
  - From Abigail Couch to Abigail Sherwood, 1808
  - From Hide to Betty Couch, 1812
  - From Solomon Morehouse to to Joseph Couch, 1812
  - From Samuel Morehouse to Joseph Couch, 1812
  - From Simon Couch to Wm. Sherwood, Jr., 1812
  - From Morehouse Coley to Joseph Couch, 1812
  - From Beaty and Taylor to Joseph Couch, 1812
  - From Joseph Couch to Daniel C. Banks, 1812
  - From James Beaty to Joseph Couch, 1813
  - From Hurlbutt and Taylor to Joseph Couch, 1813
  - From Nehemiah Couch to Joseph Couch, 1814
  - From Josiah Couch to Joseph Couch, 1814
  - From Daniel Banks to Joseph Couch, 1815
  - From Albert Chapman to Joseph Couch, 1819
  - From Hezekiah and Girshom Smith, 1819
  - From William Couch to Abigail Sherwood, 1819
  - From Zalmon Burr to Abigail Sherwood, 1822
  - From Dan Taylor to Abigail Sherwood, 1822
- Deed, Folder G; 1.0 item
  - From Nehemiah and Zebulon Couch to Neomy Couch (photocopy), 1790
- Financial Accounts, Miscellaneous, 1804-1823; Folder H; 9.0 items
- Receipts, 1722-1838; Folder I; 17.0 items
- Promissory Notes to:, 1786-1815; Folder J; 9.0 items
  - Abigail Couch, 1811
  - Samuel Couch, Jr., 1792-1808; 5.0 items
  - John Hyde, 1815
  - William Sherwood, Jr., 1814
  - Eliphalet Thorp, 1786
- Indenture and Slave Papers, 1781-1812; Folder K; 8.0 items
  - Indentures (servants)
    - Simon Couch and Joanna Lacy, 1783; 2.0 items
    - Simon Couch and Lockwood Monroe, 1807; 2.0 items
    - Simon Couch and Sarah, 1781-1782; 2.0 items
  - Slaves
    - Joseph Hawley to Simon Couch, 1789
    - William Couch to William Sherwood, Jr., 1812
- Legal Papers, Miscellaneous, 1795-1858; Folder L; 13.0 items
- Map and Military Papers, 1772-1811; Folder M; 3.0 items
  - Map of estate of Thomas Couch, 1772
  - Military certificate to Simon Couch, 1808
  - Military discharge to Simon Couch, 1811
- Probate and Wills, 1784-1815; Folder N; 9.0 items
  - Samuel Couch, 1784; 4.0 items
  - Simon Couch, 1805-1815; 4.0 items
  - Samuel Taylor, 1789
- Real Estate, 1788-1814; Folder O; 7.0 items
  - Agreements with Simon Couch, 4.0 items
  - House rents, 2.0 items
  - Inventory of Greens Farms
- Simon Couch's Yale School Papers, Folder P; 19.0 items
- Simon Couch's Yale School Papers, Folder Q; 13.0 items
- Tax lists, Folder R; 12.0 items
  - Simon Couch, 1785-1805; 7.0 items
  - unidentified, 1784-1788; 5.0 items
- Writs, 1757-1826; Folder S; 12.0 items
  - Joseph Couch vs. Benjamin Wynkop, 1757
  - Samuel Bradley vs. Solomon Couch, 1771
  - John Allen vs. Nehemiah Couch, 1772
  - Jonathan Bulkly vs. Solomon Couch, 1772
  - Solomon Couch vs. Thomas Couch, 1773
  - Benjamin Sherwood vs. Thomas Couch, 1773
  - Solomon Couch vs. Eunice Odle, 1774
  - Solomon Couch vs. John Crossman, 1774
  - Isaac Elwood vs. Simon Couch, 1787
  - Gideon Couch vs. Thomas Nash, 1791
  - Cornelius Hall vs. Simon Couch, 1797
  - Joshua Couch, et al. vs. Thos F. Rowland, 1826
- Miscellaneous and Genealogy, Folder T; 2.0 items
- Loose Papers from Simon Couch's Ledger (Oversize Item A), 1782-1894; Folder U; 19.0 items
- Loose Papers from Simon Couch's Ledger (Oversize Item B), 1795-1808; Folder V; 13.0 items
- Simon Couch's Ledgers, Folder W; 4.0 items
  - 1785-1786
  - 1787-1792
  - 1798-1800
  - 1800
- Simon Couch's Ledgers, Folder X; 5.0 items
  - 1802
  - 1803
  - 1805
  - 1805-1807
  - 1807
- Simon Couch, Jr.'s Practical Survey Book, Folder Y
- Ancestors and Descendants of Horace Smith & Elizabeth Matilda Couch, 1635-1935, Folder Z
- Simon Couch's Ledger, 1782-1794; Oversize Item A
- Simon Couch's Ledger, 1795-1808; Oversize Item B